(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.1",
"generated_at": "2026-07-26T00:24:17.005065",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.1-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
走りなさい 早く
Run, hurry up,
もっと早く 悲しみに追いつかれないように
run even faster, so sorrow doesn't catch up to you.
探しなさい 灯りのともる道を
Search for the path where the lights are lit—
それは それは 眩しいでしょう
ah, how dazzling it must be.
挑みなさい 君の美しさや尊さを傷つけ続けるものに
Challenge whatever continues to hurt your beauty and preciousness.
眠りなさい 疲れたら眠りなさい
Sleep, if you're tired, sleep.
神話を持たないあの星座のように 手を離した後
Like that constellation with no myth, after letting go of your hand,
君は気づくだろう
you will realize
指の形 太陽 その胸に噛むを
the shape of your fingers, and the sun biting into your chest.
忘れたことも 忘れてしまえ
Forget even the things you forgot.
悲しみもぬくもりも 消えてしまえ
Let both sorrow and warmth vanish.
さあとも 今も 耳に残るのは
Now and even now, what remains in your ears
たたずんだ庭を 願うような
is like wishing for the lingering garden.
I do, I do, I love you and you
踊りなさい 誰に笑われても
Dance, no matter who laughs at you,
淡雪を払おう
Let's brush off the light snow,
エントランスのように 叫びなさい
Cry out as if at an entrance,
心から叫びなさい
Cry out from the bottom of your heart,
ここに確かに出たんだと響かせて
Let it echo that you were truly here,
夕映えの空に 遠花火が滲む
Far-off fireworks bleed into the sunset sky,
帰るべき家をさがす 長い長い旅路を
On a long, long journey searching for a home to return to.
行くなら 高鳴った鐘を鳴らせ
If you're going, ring the beating bell,
鳴らせ その心臓は 最後のひとかけまで
Ring it, your heart, down to the very last piece,
君のものだ
It belongs to you.
涙た 涙た あとで泣くがいい
Tears, tears, you can cry later.
この親愛と君の周りを育てるだろう
This affection will nurture around you.
それは千年の 法螺吹きでした
That was a thousand-year-old tall tale.
無限さえも 数え終えて 怪物のような
Counting even infinity to an end, like a monster,
世界の隅っこで 戦い続けるひと 君は
Continuing to fight in the corner of the world, you are...
エロス エロス
Eros, Eros.
旅は続く 忘れたことも忘れてしまえ 悲しみも温もりも 消えちまえ
The journey continues, forget even that you forgot, let sorrow and warmth vanish too.
今を 今を 君の言葉で 強く咲いた
Now, now, with your words, blooming strongly,
愛を願うような さようなら
Like wishing for love, goodbye.
I do, I do, Have you and you
IRIS OUT
作詞・作曲：米津玄師
Lyrics & Music: Kenshi Yonezu
溜め込め 溜め込め 脳みその中から やめろ馬鹿と巡るモラリティ
Bottled up deep inside my brain, a swirling morality telling me "stop it, idiot"
ダーリン ベイビー ダーリン 半端なクラブと きらめき浮き足立つフィロソフィー
Darling, baby, darling, a half-assed club and a sparkling, restless philosophy
死ぬほど可愛い ウワメスカイ 何か四方に触れるくらい
Dying-to-be-cute upward gaze, enough to touch something on all sides
ばら撒くランシド 気づけば当時 この世に生まれて君が悪い
Scattering rancid thoughts, before I knew it, being born in this world is your fault
やたらとしんどい 恋はズバイ ばらばらなる頭とこの身体 頸動脈からアイラブユーが吹き出て
So frustratingly tiring, love is zuba! A fragmented head and this body, "I love you" gushing from my carotid artery
一体どうしよう この想いはどうしよう 暴落のクオンザラメが溶けてゲロになりそう どこをバチ開いて深海にそう
What on earth should I do, what should I do with these feelings? The sugar of a crash is melting, about to turn to vomit, opening eyes wide in the deep sea
今この世で君だけ大正解 ダーリン ダーリン...
Right now in this world, only you are the absolute right answer, darling, darling...
ひっくり返しても価値のない 君だけルールは適用外 四苦八苦を推せるのは苦しかたない 稼ぎ上げ放題
Even if you flip it over, it's worthless; only you are exempt from the rules. Struggling is unavoidable, so farm all you want
君が笑って放った 畑 食べかけ鉄骨にシグマも申し訳ねえな 譲り合って 貫いて ここ弱点
You laughed and released—a field? Half-eaten steel beams, Sigma, I'm sorry. Yielding to each other, pushing through, here is the weak point
死ぬほど可愛い ウワメスカイ 何か四方に触れるくらい ばら撒くランシド 気づけば当時 この世に生まれて君が悪い パチモンでもいい なんでもいい 今君と繋がってる全て欲しい 頸動脈からアイラブユーが吹き出て
Dying-to-be-cute upward gaze, enough to touch something on all sides. Scattering rancid thoughts, before I knew it, being born in this world is your fault. Knockoffs are fine, anything is fine, I want everything connected to you right now, "I love you" gushing from my carotid artery
IRIS OUT 一体どうしよう この想いはどうしよう 暴落のクオンザラメが溶けてゲロになりそう どこをバチ開いて深海にそう
IRIS OUT. What on earth should I do, what should I do with these feelings? The sugar of a crash is melting, about to turn to vomit, opening eyes wide in the deep sea
IRIS OUT 一体どうしよう この想いはどうしよう 暴落のクオンザラメが溶けてゲロになりそう どこをバチ開いて深海にそう 今この世で君だけ大正解
IRIS OUT. What on earth should I do, what should I do with these feelings? The sugar of a crash is melting, about to turn to vomit, opening eyes wide in the deep sea. Right now in this world, only you are the absolute right answer
永遠の意味 知らぬ君に 答えを示す時だ
It's time to show the answer to you, who knows not the meaning of eternity.
無限に続く 螺旋の先へ
Toward the endless spiral ahead.
言い訳に聞こえた理由は
The reason that sounded like an excuse
儚い未来 欲しかった弱さ
was the weakness that desired a fleeting future.
それを強さと勘違いしている
Mistaking that weakness for strength.
憎い 憎い 醜い 醜い
Hateful, hateful, so ugly, so ugly,
月を隠すほどの
enough to eclipse the moon,
黒く 黒く 淀む心
a heart dark and stagnant,
君さえ居なければ
if only you weren't here.
揺らいでいる 揺らいでいる
Swaying, swaying,
花のように 意志をつなぐ
connecting wills like flowers,
奪っていく 奪っていく
taking away, taking away,
嵐のように 心を裂く
tearing hearts apart like a storm.
永遠の意味 知らぬ君に 答えを示す時だ
It's time to show the answer to you, who knows not the meaning of eternity.
無限に続く 螺旋の先で
At the end of the endless spiral,
待つのは誰
who is waiting there?
生まれ落ちた運命を飲み込んだ
I swallowed the fate I was born into,
背負った数の名前を覚えた
memorizing the names of all I've carried.
爛れるほど 心燃やし感情
Burning my heart with festering emotions.
憎い 憎い 醜い 醜い
Hateful, hateful, so ugly, so ugly,
世界を分かちほぐほどの
enough to tear the world apart,
光り 燃やす 心
a heart burning with light,
君さえいなければ
if only you weren't here.
揺らいでいる 揺らいでいる
Swaying, swaying,
花のように 意志をつなぐ
connecting wills like flowers,
奪っていく 奪っていく
taking away, taking away,
嵐のように 心を裂く
tearing hearts apart like a storm.
永遠の意味 知らぬ君に 答えを示す時だ
It's time to show the answer to you, who knows not the meaning of eternity.
無限に続く 螺旋の先で
At the end of the endless spiral,
鬼哭に耳を傾けた仕舞いを
concluding after listening to the wails of ghosts,
この身に宿る万物で終わりを
bringing an end with all things dwelling in this body.
夢幻を他者に託した弱き人
The weak-hearted who entrusted 'Mugen' to others,
命の輝きは幾星霜に
the brilliance of life spans countless ages,
祈りの瞬きが照らす斜陽に
in the setting sun illuminated by the flicker of prayer.
千夜を身に宿し
Embracing a thousand nights within,
解を押し付ける
forcing the answer upon them.
枯らし続けている 枯らし続けている
Withered away, withered away,
夢幻の夜に花を裂く
blooming flowers in the night of 'Mugen'.
繋いでいく 繋いでいく
Connecting, connecting,
嵐に種を蒔いていく
sowing seeds in the storm.
永遠の意味 知らぬ君に 答えを示す時だ
It's time to show the answer to you, who knows not the meaning of eternity.
無限に続く 螺旋の先で
At the end of the endless spiral,
待つのわ誰
who is waiting there?
永遠の意味 知らぬ君に 答えを示す時だ
It's time to show the answer to you, who knows not the meaning of eternity.
無限に続く 螺旋の先で
At the end of the endless spiral,
待つのわ誰
who is waiting there?
ということで、ニコニコ生放送にてお届けしましたー！
And that wraps up our broadcast on Niconico Live!
お誕生日おめでとうございます！ニコニコたん！
Happy birthday! Nico Nico-tan!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
よく、おい、うるさい切れだな
Hey, your voice... jeez, you're crying!
なんかもうね、顔... 顔はもう、涙で滲んでいる
My face... my face is already blurred with tears.
「大丈夫か」って
Saying "Are you okay?"
ありがとうございまーす
Thank you very much!
いやいやいや、ありがとうございます。こちらこそ。
No, no, thank you very much, right back at you.
ということで、2026年の生誕祭はですね、
So, for the 2026 birthday celebration,
あの、ニコさんゲスト出演ということで、
we have Nico-san as a guest appearance!
はい！
Yes!
あの、ニコさんもね、3Dになってということで、
And Nico-san is now in 3D too, so...
はい！
Yes!
で、ニコさんが、いつかルイ先輩の隣で歌いたいって言ってくれてたんで、
And Nico-san had said she wanted to sing next to Lui-senpai someday,
ありがとうございます！
thank you!
なので、今日は、お呼びさせていただきました！
So, we invited her today!
ありがとうございます、本当に！
Thank you so much, really!
いや、めちゃくちゃかっこいい衣装着させていただきましたが、
Yeah, I got to wear such a cool outfit, but
皆さんいかがでしたか？
how did you all like it?
ニコたんよかったね！
Nico-tan, that was great!
ニコたんよかったねって！
そんなことよりですね、先輩！ニコたん何回…
More importantly, Senpai! Nico-tan has...
今日重大告知もあるし、
Today we have a major announcement, and
そうなんです、新衣装もあるんです、なので、
that's right, there's a new outfit too! So...
これね、たくさんね、ここのハッシュタグ「高嶺ルイ超重大生誕ライブ」ってありますんで、
there's a hashtag "#TakaneLuiSuperMajorBirthdayLive",
それでたくさん、たくさん、もうポストしてくれたら嬉しいなと思うんですけど、
and I'd be so happy if you could post lots and lots of times!
今日はたくさん告知もありますし、
Today there are lots of announcements too,
そうですよね！
That's right!
いや、ニコたん気になるのもちろん重大告知のね、デッカさも気になるんですけど、新衣装がやっぱね、気になる。
Man, Nico-tan is curious about the major announcement, how big it is, but she's really curious about the new outfit!
やっぱルイ先輩てば、ちょっとダークネスな感じなのかなとか思ったり、
Like, Lui-senpai's style usually has a bit of a darkness vibe,
暗い、黒系なのかなみたいな、あ、なるほどなるほど。
or a dark, black theme... Ah, I see, I see.
そう思いますよね！
You'd think so, right?
はい！
Yes!
ま、そうもあります。
Well, there's that too.
えー！？それも？
What?! That too?
はい！
Yes!
ということは、最初ね、あの、固定でも書かせていただいたんですけど、
Which means, as I wrote in the pinned post earlier,
新衣装は最初サブカルで、ちょっと清楚な感じの
the new outfit starts off subculture, with a slightly pure-looking
衣装になっております。
kind of outfit!
え！？それも、あ、ここにもあるってこと？
Eh?! That too? Ah, it's over here too?
はい！めちゃくちゃ大量にサブカルをご用意しておりますので、
Yes! We have a huge amount of subculture outfits prepared,
最後までね、楽しんでね！
so please enjoy it all the way to the end!
なんかすんごい騒いでる。
She's making such a fuss!
おかしいじゃん！
That's weird!
もういいや、今日来てくれてありがと！
Oh well, thanks for coming today!
わかりました！私、客席で応援してます！
Understood! I'll be cheering from the audience!
それでは！
Well then!
あ、違います違います！
Ah, wait, wait!
そちらの武道館会場なんで、
It's that Budokan venue over there, so
だめなんですかニコたん？
Is that no good, Nico-tan?
ニコたんは呼んでない。
I didn't invite Nico-tan.
招待状もらってないでしょ？
You didn't get an invitation, did you?
もらってないけど。
I didn't get one, but...
じゃあ、あの、すいませんが学屋の方に、あちらから！
Well then, um, sorry, but over to Gakuya, from over there!
あちらへ！
Over there!
はい、スタッフお願いします！
Yes, staff please!
先輩、お誕生日おめでとうございます！
Senpai, happy birthday!
ありがとう、ありがとう！大好き！
Thank you, thank you! Love you!
捕まえてください！
Catch her!
ありがとうね！
Thank you!
ということで、ニコたんに来ていただきました！
So, Nico-tan came to join us!
はい、新衣装もね、たくさん見せていきますので最後まで楽しんでいただけたらなと思います！
Yes, I'll be showing off lots of new outfits too, so I hope you enjoy it to the end!
学屋のニコたんも楽しんでくださいね！
And Gakuya's Nico-tan, enjoy it too!
それでは聴いてください、「ジグザグ」。
Now then, please listen to "ZIG-ZAG".
ワン・ツー・スリー・フォー
One, two, three, four
『幸せ？』って囀った問いが ラッタラッタラッタ
A chirped question of "Are you happy?" rat-ta-rat-ta-rat-ta
こびり付いて離れんわ 駄目だ ラッタラッタラッタ
It clings and won't let go, no good, rat-ta-rat-ta-rat-ta
無味無臭の生活が思い出せないや
I can't even remember life's blandness
忘れたいから歌った 馬鹿だ ラッタラッタラッタ
So I sang because I wanted to forget, how foolish, rat-ta-rat-ta-rat-ta
恨む事も憎む事も賢くない故出来なかった
I couldn't resent or hate, not being clever enough
これが君の結末ならば笑ってしまいたいほど嘘嘘嘘
If this is your end, it makes me want to laugh so much, lies, lies, lies
「嘘つき」
"Liar"
やだ痛い痛い痛い痛いな 奇跡とかちょっと望んじゃって
No, it hurts, hurts, hurts, hoping just a bit for a miracle
もう嫌嫌嫌嫌嫌！ 立ちが悪いわ
I hate it, hate it, hate it, hate it, hate it! Such a bad habit
ねえ辛いlie lie lie否？ おかしいとこ全部抉り取って
Hey, painful lie lie lie, no? Scooping out every strange part
薄情で結構 好きに呼んでいいよ
Call me heartless all you like, that's fine
トラウマにバイバイしたいのです で・す・で・す・で・す・です
I want to say bye-bye to my trauma, t-h-a-t-'s h-o-w i-t i-s
私、甘い上手に慣れなかった 可愛げとかが足りなかった
I couldn't get good at being sweet, lacking cuteness
後悔が煩い夜は
On nights when regret is loud
過去は過去だと割り切っちゃえば？ きっといいことあるさと
"Just write off the past as the past, and surely good things will come"?
それくらい百も承知だ ラッタッッタ
I'm fully aware of that much, rat-ta-tta
願う事も祈る事も許されないから黒く染めた
Not allowed to wish or pray, so I dyed it black
元の色も思い出せないや 絡んだ運命の糸糸糸糸
I can't even remember the original color, tangled threads of fate
やだ痛い痛い痛い痛いな 悲劇のヒロイン気取っちゃって
No, it hurts, hurts, hurts, playing the tragic heroine
もう嫌嫌嫌嫌嫌！ 諦めちえば？
I hate it, hate it, hate it, hate it, hate it! Why not just give up?
でも会いたいいたいいたいいたいな 思考回路がこんがらがっちゃって
But I want to see you, see you, see you, my thought circuits are all tangled up
明日またきっと壊すけどいいの
I'll surely break it all again tomorrow, is that alright?
トラウマさえ愛おしいのです で・す・で・す・で・す・です
Even my trauma is precious, t-h-a-t-'s h-o-w i-t i-s
夢の中で君と手を繋いでいるの 何も知らないあの頃の二人のままで
Holding hands with you in my dream, just like the two of us back when we knew nothing
でも解っているよ すぐに覚めてしまうと
But I know it will wake up right away
それならいっそ君の拠ってそっと
If so, then rather, by your side gently...
止め刺して ほら今今今！
Put an end to it, look, right now, now, now!
やだ痛い痛い痛い痛いな 奇跡とかちょっと望んじゃって
No, it hurts, hurts, hurts, hoping just a bit for a miracle
もう嫌嫌嫌嫌嫌！ 立ちが悪いわ
I hate it, hate it, hate it, hate it, hate it! Such a bad habit
ねえ辛いlie lie lie否？ おかしいとこ全部抉り取って
Hey, painful lie lie lie, no? Scooping out every strange part
薄情で結構 好きに呼んでいいよ
Call me heartless all you like, that's fine
トラウマにバイバイしたいのです で・す・で・す・で・す・です
I want to say bye-bye to my trauma, t-h-a-t-'s h-o-w i-t i-s
やだ痛い痛い痛い痛いな 奇跡とかちょっと望んじゃって
No, it hurts, hurts, hurts, hoping just a bit for a miracle
もう嫌嫌嫌嫌嫌！ 立ちが悪いわ
I hate it, hate it, hate it, hate it, hate it! Such a bad habit
ねえ辛いlie lie lie否？ おかしいとこ全部抉り取って
Hey, painful lie lie lie, no? Scooping out every strange part
薄情で結構 好きに呼んでいいよ
Call me heartless all you like, that's fine
トラウマにバイバイしたいのです で・す・で・す・で・す・です
I want to say bye-bye to my trauma, t-h-a-t-'s h-o-w i-t i-s
世界欺く 揺るぎない正義
Deceiving the world, unwavering justice—
ほどいて 真実この手の中
unwind the truth in my hands.
大胆不敵な 影が華麗に踊る
A daring, fearless shadow dances gracefully.
君が隠してる秘密 いつか聞かせてよ
Someday, let me hear the secrets you're hiding.
夢の中で君と 手をつないでいるの
Holding hands with you in my dreams...
なにも知らない あの頃の
knowing nothing at all,
二人のままで でも分かっているよ
just like those two back then, yet I know well
すぐに覚めてしまうと
that it will soon fade away.
それならばいっそ 君の手でそっと とどめを刺して
If so, then rather—gently deal the final blow with your own hands.
ほら 今すぐ
Come on, right now!
抱きしめたい 抱きしめたいな 奇跡とかちょっと望んじゃってもいい？
I want to hold you, I want to hold you... Is it okay to hope for a miracle?
手が触れる 触れないな 臆病は嫌いだから
Our hands touch, or do they not? Because I hate cowardice,
おかしこ ぜんぶ受け取って 白状して
take all my quirks in and confess!
結構好きに呼んでいいよ 想像2倍、倍、倍しての
You can call me whatever you like, with your imagination doubled!
ドレス ドレス ドレス ドレス ドレス
Dress, dress, dress, dress, dress!
世界欺く 揺るぎない正義
Deceiving the world, unwavering justice—
ほどいて 真実この手の中
unwind the truth in my hands.
大胆不敵な影が 華麗に踊る
A daring, fearless shadow dances gracefully.
君が隠してる秘密 いつか聞かせてよ
Someday, let me hear the secrets you're hiding.
アイのシナリオ 作詞・作曲：HoneyWorks
[Song: Ai no Scenario / Lyrics & Music: HoneyWorks]
大胆不敵な影が 華麗に踊る 君が隠してる秘密 いつか聞かせてよ
A daring, fearless shadow dances gracefully. Someday, let me hear the secrets you're hiding.
伸ばした手で触れる事象は 誰もできない
No one can touch it with outstretched hands.
君が隠してる世界 僕に見せてよ
Show me the world you're hiding.
揺るぎない難解な心 解き明かして奪うその瞳
Unravel my wavering, enigmatic heart and steal those eyes.
不安がって泣いていたって 見つけらんないよ
Crying out in anxiety won't help you find it.
狙う真実はどこへ消えた たとえ世界欺く解答だとしても
Where did the truth vanish? Even if it's an answer that deceives the world...
信じて差し出す掌 決して逃げない 怖くはないから
Believe in the palm I offer; I'll never run away because there's nothing to fear.
目を開け 弱さをかき消すんだ 繰り返される運命に君は気づいてる？
Open your eyes and erase your weakness. Have you noticed the repeating fate?
世界欺く解答だとしても 信じて差し出す掌
Even if it's an answer that deceives the world, believe in the palm I offer,
決して逃げない 怖くはないから
I'll never run away because there's nothing to fear.
目を開け 弱さをかき消すんだ
Open your eyes and erase your weakness.
守りたい思い出だけ ただ立ち向かって
Facing the memories I want to protect,
ほどくその絆 何度だって助けるって 揺るぎはしないよ
unraveling those bonds, and vowing to save you over and over—I won't waver.
繰り出される運命に 君は怯えてるの？
Are you frightened by the unfolding fate?
僕が隠してる秘密 いつか聞かせるよ
Someday, I'll let you hear the secret I'm hiding.
歩み寄る 偽りの影 君は知らない
You don't know the closing, deceptive shadow.
目覚めた記憶は 絡む必然の棘で
The awakened memories are tangled in inevitable thorns,
守りたい思い出だけ ただ立ち向かって
facing only the memories I want to protect.
ほどくその絆 何度だって助けるって 揺るぎはしないよ
Unraveling those bonds, vowing to save you—I will never waver.
隠す真実はどこへ消えた たとえ世界を敵に回したとしても
Where did the hidden truth vanish? Even if the whole world turns into my enemy...
信じて僕だけ 未来も 決して逃げない 迷いはないから
Believe only in me and our future; I'll never run away, with no hesitation.
シナリオ壊して抗うんだ 世界を敵に回したとしても
I'll break the scenario and fight back, even if the whole world turns against me.
信じて差し出す掌 決して離さない 答えは届いた
Believe in the palm I offer, I'll never let go—the answer has reached you.
結んだ運命この手の中 繰り返された解答だとしても
Bound fate in this hand, even if it's an answer that repeats itself...
決して逃げない 怖くはないから 抗うんだ
I'll never run away, because I'm not afraid—I will fight back!
世界欺く揺るぎない正義
Unwavering justice that deceives the world,
ほどいて真実この手の中
untying the truth in these hands.
大胆不敵な影が華麗に踊る
A daring shadow dances gracefully.
君が隠してる秘密
The secret you're hiding,
いつか聞かせてよ
let me hear it someday.
揺るむ難解な心
A wavering, hard-to-solve heart,
解き明かして奪うその瞳
solve it and steal those eyes.
不安がって泣いてたって
Even if you cry with anxiety,
見つからないよ
you won't find it.
「信じて」差し出す手のひら 決して逃さないから
"Believe in me," you hold out your palm; I will never let you escape.
逆らうんだ
I will rebel against it.
何度も何度も 走り続けるよ
Again and again, I'll keep running!
Wake up とっさに Shift up
Wake up instantly, shift up,
ぎゅっと回して Beat up ハート剥いて
spin tight, beat up, bare your heart!
U.M.A. NEW WORLD!!
ジャンプをてっぺんへ Turn up 声合わせて
Jump to the top, turn up, match our voices,
夢真未来繋いで U.M.A. NEW WORLD!!
connecting dreams and the future, U.M.A. NEW WORLD!!
最高潮 コンディション 調子ガンガン上がっていこう
Peak condition, our vibe going strong, let's climb higher!
栄光のチャンピオンコース 淡々と狙っていこう
Aim steadily for the champion course of glory!
ハイペースにマイペースに 気合入れずに調子中
At a high pace, at my own pace, tuning up without overexerting,
限るせいは限界 ハートに火が
breaking limits, fire in our hearts!
U.M.A. Let's go!
最高潮 一瞬使い切った大勝負
Peak condition, all-in for a split-second showdown,
成功のチャンスを 戦力出して掴んでいこう
grab the chance of success with all our might!
ハイペースにマイペースに 真っ最中
At a high pace, at my own pace, right in the middle of it,
駆けるロードを いつだってもっと違っていこう
let's always make our running road even more unique!
保た二人競い合った風の中ても
Even in the winds where the two of us competed,
大きな背中追いかけてた雨の中ても
even in the rain chasing that big back,
何百何千回と積み重なってきた
hundreds and thousands of times it has piled up.
だからどこまでも遠く
That's why, no matter how far,
どこまでも高く 誰よりも速く 誰よりも強く
no matter how high, faster than anyone, stronger than anyone!
咲き今駆け出した思いはもう止まらない
The feelings that started blooming now cannot be stopped!
誰にも渡せないゴールまで
All the way to the goal no one else can have,
弱気な気持ち吹き飛ばしてずっと
blown away all cowardly feelings, always
立ち上がって走り抜け 涙した鼓動は収まらない
standing up and running through, the heartbeat that shed tears won't settle!
最後まで全身全霊をかけて
Pouring my heart and soul into it until the very end,
頂点伸ばして 限界最高超えていけ
reach the peak, surpass the absolute limits!
伝説を追い越して
Surpassing legends,
勝利へ共と二人競い合ったあの喜びも
to victory, together with the joy of competing as two,
大きな背中追いかけてたあの憧れも
that longing chasing the big back too,
何百何千回と生まれ変わっても
even if we are reborn hundreds or thousands of times,
何度も何度も 走り続けるよ
again and again, I'll keep running!
駆け出した思いはもう止まらない 誰もが夢に見た未来まで
The feelings that started running can no longer be stopped, all the way to the future!
傷も傷みも愛おしい思い出だずっと 全てを抑えてゆけ
Wounds and pain are precious memories forever, suppress everything and keep going!
咲き今 駆け出した想いはもう止まらない
Blooming now, the feelings that started running cannot be stopped,
最後まで全身全霊をかけて 頂点を伸ばして
pouring heart and soul until the end, reaching the peak,
限界最高越えていけ 伝説を追い越して
surpassing maximum limits, overtaking legends,
勝利へ 共と二人競い合ったあの喜びも
to victory, the joy of competing together as two,
大きな背中追いかけてたあの憧れも
that longing chasing the big back too,
何百何千回と生まれ変わっても
even if we are reborn hundreds or thousands of times,
何度も何度も 走り続けるよ
again and again, I'll keep running!
覚ませ本能を 落とせ感動を
Awaken your instincts, let drop your emotions,
芽生えて 戦争 叫べ Break high!
budding warfare, shout "Break high!"
Woah oh oh Break high!
一体なんて壊し お得癒やすかないのか
What on earth is there to break? Isn't there any bargain healing?
寂れていく昨日までのロージ
The alleys of yesterday fading away,
後ろ向き 君返し縛んだ
looking backward, you tied it back up.
目を離さ 歴史を塗り替えてやるさ
Don't take your eyes off, I'll rewrite history!
ダン ダン ダン ダン ダン 上がっていく
Step by step, rising up,
歓声 巻き起こして Hit!
stirring up cheers, hit!
ダン ダン ダン ダン ダン 迫ってく
Closing in step by step,
あと少し 攻め合う心拍数
just a little more, heart rates battling each other.
Fight on! 挑みたい
Fight on! I want to challenge,
Fight on! つかみたい
Fight on! I want to seize it!
目覚めよ本能を
Awaken your instinct!
起こせ感動を
Stir the thrill!
刻め伝説を
Etch the legend!
叫べ break out!!
Shout break out!
革命の幕開けで
At the curtain rise of revolution,
伝説の旗掲げていこうぜ
let's hoist the flag of legend!
さぁ legend-changer
Now, legend-changer,
ロックに飛び込んで
dive into the rock beat,
熱狂起こす当事者になれ
spark the frenzy and take charge!
legend-changer 大胆に行こうぜ
Legend-changer, go bold!
本能目覚めよ 感動起こせ
Awaken instinct, stir the thrill,
伝説刻んで
etch the legend,
大地踏んづけて break!!
stomp the earth, break!
無数の足跡に見る栄冠を 憧れにして終わらせない
Don't let the glory in countless footprints end in mere longing.
託された夢が堰を切って 今、私の闘志へと変わっていく
Entrusted dreams break through, turning into my fighting spirit.
鋭い眼差し！
With a sharp gaze!
さぁ legend-changer
Now, legend-changer,
ロックに飛び込んで
dive into the rock beat,
熱狂起こす当事者になれ
spark the frenzy and take charge!
legend-changer 大胆に行こうぜ
Legend-changer, go bold!
本能目覚めよ 感動起こせ
Awaken instinct, stir the thrill,
刻め伝説を
etch the legend,
大地踏んづけて break!!
stomp the earth, break!
さぁ legend-changer
Now, legend-changer,
ロックに飛び込んで
dive into the rock beat,
熱狂起こす当事者になれ
spark the frenzy and take charge!
legend-changer 大胆に行こうぜ
Legend-changer, go bold!
本能目覚めよ 感動起こせ
Awaken instinct, stir the thrill,
刻め伝説を
etch the legend,
大地踏んづけて break!!
stomp the earth, break!
potatoになっていく
turning into potato...
もう救えない スクラブばかりのブルペンじゃ
There's no saving this bullpen full of scrubs.
ちちな青春も お涙も それすら無いもんな
Cheap youth and tears—none of that is even here.
相当に笑えない コメディのワンシーンもままならない
Not even funny; a comedy scene won't go right.
冷めたチャウダーを ただ混ぜ合わせた さも そんな人生さ
Just mixing cold chowder together, such is life.
掛け違えたボタンの身なりを いついつまでも見ぬ振りしようか
How long will we ignore these mismatched buttons?
そうかい 抗弁のしようもないな
Is that so? There's no room for protest.
たまたま火事場に逃げ込んで よかれと油を放り込んで
Stumbling into a fire and adding oil for good measure,
生活も計画も 全部がpotatoになっていく
our lives and plans are all turning into potato.
ぐつぐつ明日の泡吹いて 白目のままで湯で上がって
Simmering tomorrow, frothing at the mouth with blank eyes,
将来像 成功法 全部がpotatoになっていく
future goals, success methods—all turning into potato.
このままみんなで浸り散らして どろどろに未来を溶かして KUSHA KUSHAになっていこうぜ
Let's soak in it together, melting the future into mush until it's crumpled!
もう時間がない 我等に見下す権利などない
There's no time left, we have no right to look down.
有象無象が発した ブーイングも 今なら勲章さ
Even the mob's booing is a medal of honor now.
相当に笑えない 誰だってそう言わざるを得ない
Not funny at all, anyone would have to say the same.
バカの一つ覚えのように空回って ただバターになっている
Spinning our wheels like a fool, turning into butter.
始まりはこんなつもりじゃなかった 誰か信じてくれやしないか
It wasn't supposed to be like this. Won't someone believe me?
一切 反証の余地はないが
Though there's no room for counter-evidence.
あたかも何も知らぬ顔で ここぞと薪を投げ込んで
Acting completely innocent, throwing firewood onto the fire,
生活も 計画も 全部がpotatoになっていく
our lives and plans are all turning into potato.
こんがり明日が煮え切って 姿見えぬほど燃え上がって
Tomorrow boils over, burning up beyond recognition,
将来像 成功法 全部がpotatoになっていく
future goals, success methods—all turning into potato.
このままみんなで浸り散らして どろどろに未来を溶かして KUSHA KUSHAになっていこうぜ
Let's soak in it together, melting the future into mush until it's crumpled!
Welcome to the wonderland
こここでは誰もが見てない
Where no one looks at the cuckoo bird
How are you doing, miss?
でも何度時が過ぎても無駄
Even if your time passes and you wander in the moonlight
死ぬまで帰れない
You can't even return until you die
不気味な猫が心の中ではらう
The cat in my chest is laughing
こんなにも残してあるじゃないか
There's nothing left like this isn't it
カノン響く声にそっと耳を立てて
The resonance echoes every day
まるで理想のように
As if it's an ideal
殺されぬように
So that you won't be killed
聞かせぬように
So that you won't be found
壊れるまで愛してあげる
Until it breaks, I'll love you
快楽は繊細なの
Pleasure is delicate
どんな雲行きも焼かていぬの用に
No matter what kind of hell it is
刻み続くは
Keep engraving it deeper
Instant be so insane
そうこれは夢の中
So this is a dream within a dream
どうにかのまにか近づいてこけ ばすででもない塗りごとを
Even if we stumble closer and closer together
優しい仮面も擦り落ちそうでね
Yasashii kamen mo suriochisou de ne
ねぇいつものままどこのそれも気づかずに
Always the same, no matter what it is
If I'm dreaming then somebody look at me
Open the doorそしてメリーアンは
Open the door and then marry us
走り星がまただから歌う
Running and pushing up, from the stars we sing
誰も見えないそこで嘘を塗り潰す時
When we don't see anyone, when we paint over the lies
仮面の上が見える
The mask becomes visible
犯されないように 汚されないように
So that you won't get hurt, so that you won't get injured
地獄を咲かす花園の
Let's bloom the flower of hell
車道が欲しいなら
If you want a car and a house
膝を突き合わせるのをおやめ
Stop passing each other on your knees
差し伸べて真心を捧げて頂戴
Stretch out your hands and give me your sincere heart
It's your chance, I got all my hugs for you
Yes your majesty, I got all my hugs for you
殺せぬように 生かせぬように
So that we can kill each other, so that we can hurt each other
この狂気のジレンマさえ溢れるほど私わ
Even the madness of this moment spills over and dances
クイーンオブハート
Queen of Heart
さよなら 甘い街は
Goodbye, sweet town
私くれた人 泣き癖 笑い合い
The one who gave me my crying and laughing habits
理不尽のない喜び
A joy without logic
曖昧未完成の過ぎ 悟ったけれど
I realized my vague, imperfect mistake
それは恋の季節 閃きは戻らない
That is love's season, the spark won't return
シナリオ通りのカルマ 飛び越えてきた人生
A life spent jumping across the karma of scenarios
望みがなくなって愛だけ残ったのよ
Even if my wishes go away, only love will be left behind
それぞれの幸せ 振りかざしても
Even if we brandish our respective happinesses
倒れないふたりで立っていようね
Let's stand together as an unbreakable couple
シナリオ通りのカルマ
Karma just like the scenario,
飛び越えてきた人生
a life spent jumping across it.
望みがなくなって
My wishes faded away,
愛だけ残ったの
leaving only love behind.
それぞれの幸せ振りかざしても
Even if we brandish our own happiness,
倒れない二人で立っていようね
let's stand together as an unbreakable pair.
あでやかでいてね そのままでいてね
Stay vibrant, stay just as you are,
消えない星
an undying star.
無限クライマックス
Phantasmagorical climax,
最後の夜
the final night,
エンドレスを刻め
carve out the endlessness
斬新に
innovatively.
抱きしめても
Even if we embrace,
壊れないくらい
strong enough not to break,
強くなりすぎたから
we've grown far too strong.
あなたはわからない
You don't understand
おかえりからの孤独
the loneliness in 'welcome back'.
それでも無神経に
Yet insensitively,
季節が巡っていく
the seasons keep revolving.
いつも褒めてくれた
Always praising me,
叱ってくれた
scolding me,
きっと楽になるし
it'll surely get easier,
寂しくなるね
yet so lonely.
忘れないでいてね
Don't ever forget,
憧れていてね
keep yearning for me,
朽ちない面影
an undying visage.
だからディスティニー
So, destiny,
時を越えて
crossing through time,
同じ地球 踏んでいられるわ
we tread upon the same earth.
魂だけ
With just our souls
そばに置いてね
kept close by,
強く生きていけるの
we can live on strongly.
無限クライマックス
Phantasmagorical climax,
最後の夜
the final night,
エンドレスを刻め
carve out the endlessness
斬新に
innovatively.
抱きしめても
Even if we embrace,
壊れないくらい
strong enough not to break,
強くなりすぎた
we've grown far too strong.
寂しい
So lonely.
だからディスティニー
So, destiny,
時を越えて
crossing through time,
同じ地球 踏んでいられるわ
we tread upon the same earth.
魂だけ
With just our souls
そばに置いてね
kept close by,
強く生きていこうね
let's live on strongly.
はい、ということで、ゲストパートを見ていただきました。いかがだったですかー？
Alright, so you've seen the guest part. How was it?
いやあ、本当にね、あのゲストの人とこういうことやりたいいっていうのを、えー、実現させていただきましたー！
Man, I really got to make it happen—doing something like this with guest creators!
みなさん出演ありがとうございます。
Thank you all so much for appearing.
はい、詳しくはですね、明日の振り返り配信でいろいろね、裏話だったりとかをお話しさせていただこうかなと思いますので、ぜひ振り返り配信も来てくだ…さい。
Right, details will be shared in tomorrow's recap stream with behind-the-scenes stories, so please come check that out too.
そして、いかがですか？衣装は。いかがでしょうか？かわいいでしょう？
And how do you like the outfit? How is it? Isn't it cute?
たくさんあの、差分があったんですけど、気付きましたか？まあ気付きますよね。
There were a lot of variations, did you notice? Well, of course you did.
最初は白い衣装から始まりまして、そして「ウマ娘」ワールドではですね、あの黒いパンツ姿で階段から、あそこの階段から登場したんですけれども、
It started with the white outfit, and then in the 'Uma Musume' world, I appeared in black pants coming down that staircase over there.
最初みんな、え、ルイどこ？みたいな、感じになってて面白かったんですけど、
At first everyone was like, 'Wait, where's Lui?' which was hilarious.
なんかね、ウマ娘を知ってる人は、まああそこから来るんやろなって、なんか、候補腕組みしてたのがまた面白かったですね。
Those who know Uma Musume probably guessed she'd come from there, standing with arms crossed, which was also funny.
はい。えー、面会、あのこのあとですね、えー、21時20分から、えー、面会で撮影会もございますので、そちらも是非いろんな差分を見せていきたいなと思いますので、撮影会もぜひ来ていただけたら嬉しいでございます。
Also, right after this at 21:20, we have the meeting and photo session, where I'll be showing off various other expressions, so I'd be so happy if you could join us there!
はい。えー、重大発表はですね、こ、あと2曲なんですけど、えー、今から歌う曲の後で、えー、発表させていただきますので、ぜひ皆さん、ちょっと心待ちにしていただけたらなと思います。
Now, as for the major announcement, we have just two songs left, and I'll announce it right after the song I'm about to sing, so please look forward to it!
はい。えー、じゃあ次の曲はですね、鷹嶺ルイセカンドアルバム『ラピスラズリ』から1曲歌わせていただきます。「抗う君への鎮魂歌」です。お願いします。
Alright. So for the next song, I'll be singing a track from my 2nd album 'Lapis Lazuli'. It's called 'Requiem for Resisting You'. Here it is.
抗う君への鎮魂歌
Requiem for Resisting You
正しさだけ纏える術があれば
If there were a way to wear only righteousness,
少しは救われるだろうか
would I be saved even a little?
その瞳へと問いかける
I ask those eyes.
護るべきを捨てるべきと誰かに咎められても
Even if someone rebukes me for abandoning what should be protected,
心通わないならそれは虚言だ
if our hearts don't connect, it's all a lie.
何も捨てずに抗う力なき亡者
Powerless ghosts fighting without abandoning anything,
その覚悟無き創造に正しさなどない
there is no righteousness in such resolve-less creation.
失えば失うほどに更に気高くその意志で世界を恨め
The more I lose, the prouder I become; with that will, curse the world.
心が砕けて何度引き裂かれようと抗え
Even if my heart breaks and is torn apart over and over, fight on.
弱き一人を護り抜くためのこの手掌がどれだけ汚れてしまっても
No matter how stained these palms become in protecting that one weak person,
構わないさ君が笑うなら僕はなんでもなる
I don't care, if you smile, I will become anything.
浅ましい擬態へつらうだけなら人も獣も何一つ変わらない
If it's just flattering a pathetic disguise, humans and beasts are no different at all.
鎖に似た自由を嘆いてはびくつ気に愛でるのだろう
Lamenting freedom like a chain, trembling as you cherish it.
どうか君だけは僕を覚えていて欲しい
Please, I want you alone to remember me.
必ず君を自由へと誘う
I will surely guide you to freedom.
俯けば俯くほどに更に気高くその意志で世界を揺らし
The more I hang my head, the prouder I become; shake the world with that will,
心が歪んで何もかもが崩れても抗え
and even if my heart warps and everything crumbles, fight on.
弱き一人を護り抜くためのこの手掌がどれだけ汚れてしまっても
No matter how stained these palms become in protecting that one weak person,
構わないさ君が笑うなら
I don't care, if you smile,
壊して見せる心から君が笑えた時僕は報われるのだろう
I'll show you I can break it; when you can smile from the bottom of your heart, I will be rewarded.
はいということで、私鷹嶺ルイの初めてのソロライブが決定しましたイエーイ！
So, with that said, my very first solo live has been decided! Yay!
会場はカナデビアホールです。
The venue is Kanadevia Hall.
そして12月に鷹嶺ルイのソロライブがあるということで、
And in December, Takane Lui's solo live!
1年ね、2026年はすごい楽しめる年なんじゃないですか、ルイ友さ （笑）
2026 is going to be such a fun year, right, Lui-to-mosa? (Laughs)
はい。ということで、ルイ友さんにはね、色々お話ししたことがあると思うんですけれど、
Right. So, speaking of various things with Lui-tomosa,
ファーストライブから少しずつ段階階段を上がっていって、
starting from the 1st live, step by step, climbing the stairs,
広い会場でソロライブをするというそんな物語に憧れていました。
and doing solo lives in larger venues—I've been longing for that story.
だからもし私がライブをやることになった際には、ファースト、セカンド、サード、フォースと、
So I've always told Lui-tomosa that if I ever get to do a live,
順順に会場を大きくしてゆくゆくはアリーナという夢を叶えたい、
I want to make it an arena one day.
はい、そう思っていた、え、ルイ友さんにはね、え、常々お伝えをしていたと思います。え、そのためにね、定期的なソロライブができる活動を頑張りたいなと思って今まで努力を、え、してきました。そしてこれからも、します。
So I've been working hard to make regular solo lives happen, and I'll keep doing so!
はい。
(Laughs)
最近のホロライブはですね、結構より多くの方が入る会場での開催が多くて、私の夢はちょっと難しいのかなとは思っていたんですけど、こうやって私の夢を理解してくださり、叶えて、え、叶えるべく、まずは私の希望だったカナデビアホールにてファーストライブをさせていただくことになりました！おめでとう！ありがとう！そして、あのトレンドもありがとうございます。ありがとうございます。
Recent hololives are often held in larger venues, so I thought my dream might be difficult. But seeing you understand and fulfill it—first, by letting me have my first solo live at Kanadevia Hall, my dream venue! Congratulations, and thank you! And thank you for the trending topic too. Thank you.
え、ここからが鷹嶺ルイの新章の、え、新章の物語の始まりでございます。
Here starts the story of Takane Lui's new chapter.
まずはファーストライブをね、開催してから次を考えるべきだとは思うんですけど、
First, we'll hold the 1st live, and then think about what's next.
私はセカンド、サード、フォース、その先のライブへのビジョンまで考えております。はい。今回の生誕ライブのタイトルでもあるように、Luminous Stairs、輝かしい階段を駆け上がるために、
The live title is...
ライブのタイトルは、REBELLIONになっております。
REBELLION.
はい、REBELLIONです。はい、反逆という意味でございます。私がいつも抱えている不安や、そして色々な否定の声、そして私自身の葛藤、え、これからも私は、え、それを私の歌で反逆していきたい、そんな気持ちで込めさせて、え、込めてつけさせていただきました。最高のライブになるようにたくさん準備をしていますので、ぜひ楽しみに待っていてください。
Thank you so much.
はい、ここからまた新たに鷹嶺ルイの物語が始まるということで、
And now, to kick off this new story,
アーティスト写真を作りました！こちらです。
I've created a new artist photo! Here it is.
はい、めちゃくちゃかっこいいですね。かっこかわいい。はい、アーティスト活動の際にはこちら使っていこうかなと思っておりますので、よろしくお願いいたします。
Pretty cool, right? Cool and cute. I plan to use this for artist activities, so I'd appreciate your support!
そして、ここまでファースト、セカンド、アコースティックとアルバムを作ってきましたが、今回ライブ、え、ライブを盛り上げるために4曲、はい、え、新しく作りまして収録させていただいたミニアルバムも本日ライブ終了後に予約開始です。
Up until now, I've released 1st and 2nd acoustic albums, but to amp up this live, I've prepared and recorded 4 new tracks for a mini-album, which will be available to preorder right after today's live!
ね、たくさん曲がありますね、鷹嶺ルイ。はい。え、じゃあ、え、レジェンダリーという、はい、タイトルをつけさせていただきましたミニアルバムでございます。この後にね、披露する新曲も入っております。え、完全生産限定盤には全員にサインが付きます。はい。完全生産限定盤には全員に、え、直筆サインが付きますので、はい、ぜひ日頃の感謝を込めてサインを書きますのでぜひ予約してください。
There are so many tracks, Takane Lui! (Laughs) Well, the mini-album is titled "LEGENDARY". It includes the new songs, and the limited production edition comes with a signed leather jacket for everyone!
お求めやすい通常盤もあります。こちらはちょっとサインついてないんですけど、はい、通常盤もございますのでぜひお手元に、え、取っていただけますと嬉しいです。今回のライブ、そして、え、この後に予約開始されるミニアルバムのハッシュタグは共通で、ハッシュタグ鷹嶺ルイの反逆となっております。
And the hashtag for both the live and the upcoming mini-album is just "#TakaneLuiRebellion".
はい、皆さんたくさんポストして盛り上げてくださいね。美ジュ良いっしょ？美ジュ良いよね。
Please post lots and get hyped!
以上ソロライブとミニアルバムのお知らせでした。まだお知らせはございます。はい、お知らせと重大告知が次はお待ちかねのグッズ紹介です。はい、こちら。鷹嶺ルイ誕生日記念2026ということで、
Next up, we have birthday merchandise to introduce! Here they are.
キービジュアルはですね、
The key visual features me
今回お披露目させていただいた新衣装を着て
wearing our newly unveiled outfit
ケーキを食べている鷹嶺ルイです。
and eating cake, that's me, Takane Lui.
久乃のり先生に写真を撮っていただきました。可愛いでしょう？
Hisano Nori-sensei took this photo for me. Isn't it cute?
それでは1つずつ見ていきましょう。
Let's take a look at them one by one.
1つ目はこちら、アクリルジオラマスタンドになっております。
First up is this acrylic diorama stand.
キービジュアルを使用したアクリルジオラマになっております。
It's an acrylic diorama featuring the key visual.
瑠伊友さんとですね、ガモも可愛く羊風におめかしをしてます。可愛い！
Ruitomos and Gamo are dressed up adorably like sheep. So cute!
続いてはこちら。
Next is this.
新衣装にね、え、こちら、新衣装の、はい、こちらのとかについている、え、2種類のエンブレムをモチーフにしたピンバッチでございます。
These pin badges are based on the two types of emblems found on the new outfit.
いろんなところに付けてひそかに瑠伊友アピールをしてください。おしゃれでしょ？
Pin them anywhere to subtly show your Ruitomo pride. Isn't it stylish?
続いてはこちら。新衣装をモチーフにしたポーチになっております。おしゃれ。
Next is this pouch featuring the new outfit motif. Very stylish.
裏面はですね、メッシュポケットになっているので缶バッチはもちろんなんですけど、今回一緒にね、販売するピンバッチもつけやすいデザインになっております。
The back has a mesh pocket, making it easy to attach not only can badges but also the pin badges we're selling this time.
最後は、これ欲しかったんじゃないかな？こちら。
And finally, something you must have wanted: this!
はい、新衣装のショートパンツバージョンのホロライブと同じくらいのサイズのぬいぐるみです。可愛い！
Yes, a plushie in the same size as hololive's short pants version of the new outfit. So cute!
ぜひこの機会にお迎えしていただけたら嬉しいです。よろしくお願いします。
I'd be so happy if you could welcome one home this time. Thank you!
フルセット購入特典はこちら。
The full set purchase bonus is right here.
ポストカードになっておりまして、数量限定版と通常版がございます。
It's a postcard, available in a limited quantity version and a regular version.
数量限定版は、え、直筆サインが付きます。たくさん用意して、お、おるので、ま、ゆっくり、ゆっくり選んでください。
The limited quantity version comes with a handwritten signature. We've prepared plenty, so please take your time choosing.
え、販売時間はですね、少し余裕を持たせて21時15分からカートオープンです。
Sales will open at 21:15 with a little extra time.
はい、以上グッズ紹介でした。
Yup, that concludes the merchandise introduction!
そしてもう1つ、重大告知です。こちら。
And now, another major announcement: this!
なんと私が夢見ていましたBAYFMさんにてレギュラーラジオの番組が決定しました！放送日はですね、毎週金曜日24時30分から24時57分、初回放送日は7月3日金曜日となっております。
I've been dreaming of this—I'm getting my own regular radio show on BAYFM! It will air every Friday from 24:30 to 24:57, starting on Friday, July 3rd!
Xでも初回配信用ののお便りを募集するので、はい、メールアドレスも公開しますので、Xのフォローをよろしくお願いいたします。楽しみにしててね。
We'll also be calling for letters for the first broadcast on X and sharing the email address, so please follow us on X. Look forward to it!
はい、次の曲が最後の曲になります。先ほどもね、紹介させていただきました新曲になっておりまして名前はSoarと言います。
Now, the next song will be the final one. As I introduced earlier, the new song is titled "Soar."
ソロライブでもみんなとね、一緒に歌いたいなと思って、みんなが声出しできる新曲を作って来ました。七星さんに書き下ろしていただいた爽やかな楽曲になっております。
I created this new song so we can all sing along together during my solo live, with parts where everyone can voice out. It's a refreshing track written by Nanahoshi-san.
この後21時から、21時ちょっと過ぎかもしれないけど、ミュージックビデオのプレミア公開もあります。
Right after this at 21:00—maybe just past 21:00—the music video premiere will also go live.
楽曲は本日24時にリリースです。この曲はですね、コーラスはホロメンが歌ってくれております。ライブまでにたくさん聴いて覚えてくれたら嬉しいです。
The song releases tonight at 24:00. Hololive members provided the chorus for this track. I'd be so happy if you listen to it a lot and learn it by the live!
では早速聴いていただきましょう。皆さんと一緒に歌いたい曲Soarです。どうぞ。
Now, let's listen to it right away. The song I want to sing together with everyone, "Soar." Here it is.
何度でも君を呼んで また歩いてゆく
Calling out your name over and over, I'll walk on once again.
Soar
一歩踏み出したらもう未来さ
The moment I take a step, it's already the future.
昨日つまずいた道も 今日からは近道だ
Even the road I stumbled on yesterday is a shortcut from today.
息をするたびに広がる景色
The scenery expands with every breath I take.
私を信じていいと言って
Tell me it's okay to believe in myself.
つぶやきも希望になって あふれては声になって
Murmurs turn into hope, overflowing into a voice.
何度目を閉じても消えないな
No matter how many times I close my eyes, it doesn't fade away.
高く飛べるよそうだろう 抑えられない
I can fly high, right? I can't hold it back.
羽ばたく理由を誰かに許されなくても
Even if no one permits me the reason to spread my wings,
もう決めたよ迷わない 向かい風も きっと進んでる証拠だって
I've already decided, I won't hesitate. Headwinds are proof that I'm moving forward—
君に伝えるんだ
I'll tell you that!
どんな重力も心までは 縛れない 曲げられない
No gravity can bind or bend my heart.
この手で確かめたい
I want to confirm it with my own hands.
胸焦がした思いで 爪痕をさぁ刻んで
With feelings that scorched my heart, come carve our mark.
嵐の空模様 切り裂いて
Slash through the stormy sky.
もっと輝くよ そうだろう 叫べばいい
I'll shine even brighter, right? Just shout it out!
憧れより眩しい歌 そして激しい歌
A song more dazzling than longing, and a fierce song
いつか耳を塞いだ その両手が きっと翼になる
Those hands that once covered my ears will surely become wings
そう思うんだ
That's what I believe
ゆずれない衝動
An unrelenting impulse
高く飛べるよ そうだろう 抑えられない
I can fly high, right? I can't hold it back
羽ばたく理由を 誰かに許されなくても
Even if no one permits the reason for my wings to flutter
もう決めたよ 迷わない 向かい風も きっと進んでる証拠だって
I've decided, I won't hesitate. Headwinds are proof I'm moving forward!
君に伝えるんだ
I'll convey it to you
何度でも君を呼んで また歩いてゆく
Calling out to you again and again, I'll keep walking forward
皆さん本日は生誕祭に来て下さってありがとうございました！
Thank you all so much for coming to my birthday live today!
ソロライブ楽しみにしててね！
Look forward to my solo live too!
バイバーイ！
Bye-bye!